## **Christina Van Heer**

## **Computational Scientist**

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

- **1** Christina Van Heer
- Melbourne
- **▼** Incibodi

否 -

- christinavanheer@gmail.com
  www.linkedin.com/in/christina-van
  - heer
  - https://github.com/cavnheer



2010

2018

## My publications

## **EDUCATION**

2016PhD Candidate (Part time),
Cognitive Computational Cognitive
Science - Modelling Human
Learning Under Uncertainty

2012 Post Graduate Diploma

2011 Graduate Diploma (Psychology)

Bachelor of Science (Chemistry)
Major: Chemistry
Monash University

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

2019 Invited Talk: Australian Cognitive
Neuroscience Society Conference,
University of Tasmania

Invited Workshop: R analysis and ggplot2 for beginners

Best Speaker: Psychological Sciences PhD Conference

Invited Talk: Ecole Normale Supérieure, and NeuroSpin Research Institute, Paris.

Selected from over 300 candidates to attend a 2-week international computational modelling workshop in Burgundy, France.

#### **ABOUT ME**

Driven and enthusiastic computational scientist with 7 years experience working with complex statistical models. Strong communicator with recognised excellence in modelling. Thorough planner and problem solver who can work independently and as part of a team.

## **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

**Computational modelling skills** Seven years experience using complex statistical models to *explain and predict data*. Expertise in multiple coding languages (R, Python, Javascript, SQL)

**Problem solving** Can break down highly complex questions, from design, through to coding, implementation, online delivery and statistical modelling, and visualisation. Can troubleshoot projects step by step under time constraints.

**Building and maintaining relationships with stakeholders** Experienced in building and maintaining relationships with stakeholders and managing competing interests across the public sector.

**Communication** Skilled scientific communicator who is passionate about breaking down complex problems into easy-to-understand language, and have presented my research both nationally and internationally.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Senior Analyst Modelling and analytics team (Sep 2021 - Present)

Forward Strategy Team, Department of Health (Feb 2021 - Aug 2021)

### Key responsibilities

- Providing strategic advice and modelling around the risk factors for hospitalisation, isolation, testing and quarantine scenarios
- Development of reporting metrics to visualise and asses case and hospitalisation, and incursion risk via daily and weekly dashboards
- Modelling of risks associated with travel and quarantine of travellers from high prevalence countries of interest
- Analytics support to the Forward Strategy Team on the COVID-19 response via daily, weekly and monthly strategy analysis and reporting to the Public Health, Secretary and Health Minister's teams in a time sensitive manner for cabinet meetings and press conferences.

## **Key achievements**

- Advice from modelling was used to inform testing strategies for The Australian Open and Grand Prix, together with colleagues from Public Events, and Jobs Precincts and Regions
- Modelling of risk factors associated with hospitalisation is actively being used to inform triage related cutoffs for the covid positive pathways program in Victoria

## **Christina Van Heer**

Teaching Assistant, Complex Human
Data Modelling Summer School, The
University of Melbourne
Delivered workshop: R and ggplot2
for beginners, University of
Melbourne PhD Camp

Secretary, Graduate Students
in Psychological Sciences

Research and Research Training
Committee Representative, The
Invited Talk: Cognitive Lunch Series,
The University of Melbourne

Assistant, Research Platforms R

workshop, The University of

Neuroscience Conference,

Best Speaker: Australian Cognitive

## **REFEREES**

2015

# Daniel West Director, Modelling and Analytics Department of Health

daniel.west@health.vic.gov.au

## Dr Jose Canevari Manager, Analytics

jose.canevari@health.vic.gov.au

## Kylie Reid

# Manager, Monash Biomedical Imaging Monash University:

kylie.reid@monash.edu +61 3 9902 0581

## Associate Prof. Andrew Perfors, Deputy Head, Complex Human Data Hub, The University of Melbourne:

perfors@gmail.com +61 420 765 695

## Technical Officer, Monash Biomedical Imaging (2017 - Feb 2021) Key responsibilities

- Setup and troubleshooting of human neuroimaging, behavioural and genetic projects in mental illness, neurological disorders and health (exercise) research areas.
- Programming (MATLAB, Python) and technical support for researchers
- Writing risk, compliance and SOP documentation for researchers
- Training of all new users in human neuroimaging equipment (EEG, MRI, MR-PET, eyetracking).
- · On-call troubleshooting and coding support.

#### **Achievements**

- Overseen (30+) research projects to completion with national and international research partners.
- Over 500 jobs logged and resolved as part of a support team of 2 staff.

## Senior Statistics Tutor, The University of Melbourne (2015 - 2020) Key responsibilities

- Teaching weekly 1 hour tutorials to third year students using R.
- · Content development (slides and code).
- Marking of assignments.

#### **Achievements**

- · Nominated for a teaching award.
- Successfully pivoted to teaching online in 2020
- Many of my students have gone on to further study in psychology (honours, masters, PhD).

# Research Assistant - Vision and Attention Laboratory (2016), The University of Melbourne

## **Key responsibilities**

- Coding and supervision of experiments for an honours student project
- · Developing and coding experiments.
- Computational modelling and data analysis using MATLAB and R.

#### **Achievements**

 My work resulted in 1 peer reviewed publication in Psychonomic Bulletin and Review.

## Research Assistant / Lab Manager - Decision Neuroscience Laboratory The University of Melbourne (2014 - 2016)

## **Key responsibilities**

- Used machine learning methods and statistical analyses to predict human brain activity and behaviour via survey-based methods.
- Developing and coding experiments.
- Dealing with grant bodies and other stakeholders, recruitment, and maintaining financial and data records.

#### **Achievements**

- 1 peer reviewed publication in *Social Cognitive Affective Neuroscience*
- Built and maintained large scale collaboration between researchers
   The University of Cologne and The University of Melbourne.
- Ran a neuroimaging study (budget: \$30 000) in 6 months.
- Contributed code which was developed into a free toolbox